PIERRE GUINOISEAU

Site Reliability Engineer

contact

summary

pierre@guinoiseau.nz +64 29 126 7846 linkedin://pierreguinoiseau

I'm a 32 years old Frenchman in New Zealand with 12+ years experience as a Linux/Unix systems engineer, Site Reliability Engineer / DevOps engineer and Go, Python, Ruby developer. I'm looking for my next adventure!

languages

experience

French: native English: fluent Spanish: notions Te Reo Māori: learning

2018–2020 **Magic Leap**

Wellington, New Zealand

programming

Go, Python, ♥ Ruby

Lead Site Reliability Engineer

Magic Leap, Inc. is an American startup company that released a head-mounted virtual retinal display, called Magic Leap One, which superimposes 3D computer-generated imagery over real world objects, by "projecting a digital light field into the user's eye", involving technologies potentially suited to applications in augmented reality and computer vision.

As a Lead Site Reliability Engineer, I worked remotely in an international team to ensure the safe, swift, and reliable delivery of services to the company's customers. My role combined software and systems engineering to deliver highly scalable, distributed, fault tolerant systems.

My responsabilities included:

- developing solutions to increase service stability through automation and process re-engineering;
- building and supporting tools and systems that software engineers use to deploy their software into production, contributing to a great extent to an internal build tool written in Go wrapping Terraform operations;
- participating in rotating on-call duties in a global 24×7×365 team;
- updating job knowledge by studying state-of-the-art tools and techniques;
- helping development teams operationalize their efforts to enable selfownership of production services.

2015-2018

Catalyst IT

Wellington, New Zealand

DevOps engineer / PHP and Python developer

Catalyst IT is a global team of skilled open source technologists, specializing in developing, designing and supporting enterprise grade systems using open source technologies.

As a DevOps engineer, I worked in the eLearning team, delivering, customizing and hosting Moodle and Totara LMS sites for schools, universities, corporations and government organisations. My role consisted in building and maintaining our CI and deployment tools and helping with infrastructure changes, as well as doing some backend development on those sites. I also helped with some web development on PaCT (Progress and Consistency Tool), built with Django.

Linux/Unix systems engineer / DevOps engineer

M6 Web, the M6 Group's subsidiary responsible for developing new technologies, is structured around several operational platforms: websites of TV channels, offering Catch-up TV and VOD, thematic web portals, comparison shopping websites, mobile phones with M6's Mobile by Orange offer, and finally games and channel interactivity.

As a member of a small Linux/Unix systems engineering team working together with a remote ops team, I was in charge of the hosting infrastructure, spread across 2 datacenters and AWS, and the local development platform, for a total of 400+ physical and virtual heterogenous hosts hosting 150+ websites and webservices.

As we started to adopt agile methods, I focused mainly on providing developers an environment and tools that would enable them to develop and deploy their products in an automated, fast and reliable way.

2008–2010 Pilot Systems

Lyon & Paris, France (remote work)

Python/Zope/Plone developer and Linux/Unix system administrator

Pilot Systems is an Open Source Integrator, specializing in Python solutions, like Zope, Plone, Django, etc.

As a developer, I worked on the development and maintenance of intranet and extranet solutions for several customers, based on Zope (2.x) and Plone (2.x and 3.x), as well as the maintenance and a major migration of a major French newspaper's website.

As a system administrator, I maintained and modernized the company's hosting infrastructure, and provided systems engineering consulting for some customers.

2007–2008 **Eliot**

Web developer and embedded system developer — Part-time internship

Eliot designs and produces modular on-board telematic Solutions for transport (goods and passenger), logistics and industrial companies.

As a student intern, I had 2 different missions in parallel:

- developed an API around a proprietary mapping, routing and geocoding server (deCarta DDS) that could be used in a backoffice software;
- tested a next-generation on-board terminal running Embedded Linux OS on an ARM platform.

education

2007–2008 **Bachelor's Degree** in Computer Science Université Pierre Mendès-France (Grenoble II) Licence professionnelle "Systèmes Informatiques et Logiciels" (Information Systems

and Softwares)

and Soπwares

2005–2007 **Associate's Degree** in Computer Science Université Pierre Mendès-France (Grenoble II) DUT Informatique (Higher National Diploma in Technology / Computer Science)

skills

• **Programming languages:** Go, Python, ♥ Ruby

• Operating systems: Linux (Gentoo, Debian, Ubuntu, RedHat), ♥ FreeBSD, OpenBSD

• Cloud computing platforms: AWS, GCP

• Virtualization: VMWare ESX(i), Xen

• Infrastructure as Code: CloudFormation, Terraform

• Containerization: Docker

• Configuration management: Puppet + MCollective, Chef, Ansible

• CI: ♥ Gitlab CI, Bitbucket Pipelines, Concourse, Jenkins, GoCD

• SCM platforms: ♥ GitLab, GitHub, Bitbucket

• **Logging, monitoring:** Datadog, Sentry, SumoLogic, Prometheus, StatsD+Graphite+Grafana, Cacti, Nagios/Icinga

interests

Playing guitar, drumming, photography, longboarding, hiking, martial arts, sharing craft beers with my friends.

referees

Available on request.